justtotaltech.co.uk 2014-03-15

# Just Total Tech Privacy Policy

**_Date of Last Update: December 15, 2011_**

 **This policy will let you know:**

  1. What personally identifiable information does Common Application collect from you?
  2. What are cookies and how are they used?
  3. How does Common Application use applicant information?
  4. How does Common Application use school official information?
  5. Who is collecting your information?
  6. With whom does Common Application share your information?
  7. What is Common Application’s policy when there has been an allegation of fraud, misrepresentation or other inappropriate act involving an applicant?
  8. What are the applicant’s choices are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of your information, including your rights to “opt-in” or “opt-out”?
  9. What is Common Application’s policy on allowing you to access, update, correct, or delete your personally identifiable information?
  10. What are the kind of security precautions that are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information, including your credit card information and how is your information stored, accessed and used by others?
  11. Your California privacy rights;
  12. Does Common Application have an identity theft policy?
  13. What kinds of patterns, practices or activities may indicate the existence of identity theft?
  14. What steps does Common Application take to detect identity theft or breaches of personal data?
  15. What steps does Common Application take to safeguard against, respond to and/or mitigate continued or future identity theft or breaches of personal data?
  16. Additional information and how you can contact us regarding this Policy.
  17. Emails that you send us

Through our trustworthy independent web service provider, Common Application’s web site (www.justtotaltech.co.uk) collects, uses, and distributes to those member Colleges and/or Universities that you select personally identifiable information collected about you on-line. Please read carefully the following Privacy Policy before registering with us and completing an on-line user registration form. Please note that this Policy only addresses Common Application’s privacy practice concerning information collected from its own web site and does not apply to information that may have been collected about you by others. This Policy also does not cover the privacy or information practices of those web sites that may be linked to the Common Application web site or the privacy or information practices of those Colleges and/or Universities that receive the personal information that is collected from our site and distributed to them as part of the application admissions process. Please also note that this Policy may change from time to time so please check back to review this Policy each time you visit or use the web site.

 **Changes in this Privacy Policy Statement:**

If we decide to change our Privacy Policy or email practices we will post those changes to this Privacy Policy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this Policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.

 **What personally identifiable information does Common Application collect from you?**

Through our trustworthy independent web service provider, Common Application collects information in several ways from different parts of our web site.

Whenever you visit the site, the web server may automatically collect the IP address of the computer you are using. We will also likely save the phone numbers, email addresses, web browsers and operating systems of those users that send us “Technical Support” requests.

Certain required and optional personal information (such as your name, home and mailing address, email address, telephone number, citizenship, date and place of birth, parents’ names and address, social security number) is collected from you when you voluntarily provide this information to us through the completion of an on-line User Registration form and/or when you voluntarily complete the Common Application®, any application supplements, or other applicant forms. During registration, Common Application asks you to create a username and password. Once you register you are no longer anonymous to Common Application – you are given a Common Application User ID and are able to take full advantage of Common Application’s on-line services. You can also enter your credit card information at a different location on the site to pay for admission application fees for the member Colleges and/or Universities that you select. See “The kind of security precautions that are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information, including your credit card information and how is your information stored and accessed by others” on how we keep your credit card information secure.

Wherever we collect personal information we make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page.

 **What are cookies and how are they used?**

A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

We do not install any third party programs or cookies on the user’s computer, nor do we store any personal information via cookies. However, cookies are used for managing your on-line sessions while you are visiting the site.

This Privacy Policy statement covers the use of cookies by the Common Application only and does not cover the use of cookies by any linked websites.

 **How does Common Application use your information?**

When you seek to register with us, complete a Common Application®, an application supplement and/or other applicant form, we need to know your name, email address, and mailing address among other items of personal information. See “What personally identifiable information is collected from you.” This information, requested by the Colleges and/or Universities, allows them to identify you and process your application upon submission.

Unless you affirmatively select the “opt-in” option described in the Section entitled “What are your choices regarding collection, use and distribution of my information, including your rights to “opt-in” or “opt-out,” users of the web site who use our services to apply to various member Colleges and/or Universities will not receive any College/University specific information concerning their respective admissions process; however, we may use your email address to send you registration and submission confirmation emails, or we may need to contact the user/applicant to help answer a technical support question that you may have posed to us regarding your use of the site.

 **How does Common Application use school official information?**

By registering with our site your collected personal information may be shared and used by our member colleges and/or universities to contact you at any time and for any reason. This information includes your name, your official title, your email address and zip code, school code information and date, as well as the student applicant’s name. Also, if you submit your credit card payment information to us in order to purchase copies of any Common Application® form in order to transmit recommendations, transcripts and/or admission related documents about a student as part of your evaluation in the student admissions process, rest assured that Common Application and its independent trustworthy service providers know NOT to provide student applicants with access to any applicant specific data that you have created in connection with their admission to the member college or university of their choice where there is an expectation of confidentiality and privacy on your part.

Unless you affirmatively select the “opt-in” option described in the Section entitled “What are your choices regarding collection, use and distribution of my information, including your rights to “opt-in” or “opt-out,” users of the web site who use our services to apply to various member Colleges and/or Universities will not receive any College/University specific information concerning their respective admissions process; however, we may use your email address to send you registration and submission confirmation emails, or we may need to contact the user/applicant to help answer a technical support question that you may have posed to us regarding your use of the site.

 **Who is collecting information?**

When you are on the Common Application site and are asked for and provide personal information, this information is being collected by our trustworthy independent web service provider who provides all of the technical support, including collection, storage and protection of your personal information, in order to allow Common Application to offer our service to you. There is no attempt to collect or compare personal information about you from sources other than what you voluntarily provide to us when using the web site.

 **With whom does Common Application share your information?**

Common Application shares your personal information (including your email address) with our trustworthy independent web service provider who then only shares your personally identifiable information (including your email address) with those member Colleges and/or Universities with whom you select. Only your credit card information is shared with the credit card processor that you have chosen in order to consummate on-line the payment of admission application fees to the Colleges and/or Universities you have selected. By voluntarily providing us with your personal information, you are giving us your express consent to share your personal information with the aforementioned parties (and subject to this Policy) so that we can provide the service for which you have registered. Note that even if you never submit an application through the Common Application, the Colleges and/or Universities will still have access to the personal information that you had voluntarily submitted on any application supplement, payment or other applicant or admission related form, and such Colleges and/or Universities may contact you even prior to the time your application is submitted.

While Common Application requires that each member College and University sign a _Participation Agreementeach_ year pledging that they will accept the Common Application® without prejudice, fully support its use and that they each agree to the _Statement of Principles and Practices for Members_ , Common Application is not responsible for the failure of any College or University to accept the Common Application® or how any given College or University (after accessing or receiving your personal information from us) will use, protect or store the information in their possession. You are encouraged to review that College/University’s individual privacy policies and information practices as to how they use and protect your personal information and Common Application neither accepts nor assumes any liability or responsibility for the use or protection of your personal information by said College or University.

 **What is Common Application’s policy when there has been an allegation of fraud, misrepresentation or other inappropriate act involving an applicant?**

Members, secondary schools and applicants are advised that The Common Application functions and solely views itself as a conduit of information between the student applicant, his/her secondary school and the various member Colleges and Universities selected by the applicant.  As such, it is Common Application’s policy not to judge, evaluate, conduct any verification of or perform an investigation on any data provided on or about a student applicant regardless of the source of that data.  That said, where we have been informed of an act of fraud, misrepresentation or other inappropriate act involving an applicant, The Common Application reserves the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law or in any instance or circumstance when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, the rights of our members and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, police investigation, court order, or legal process served on our Web site. Subject to any rights afforded by law, Common Application also reserves the right upon notice to an applicant to disclose information collected from a registered user about which member Colleges and/or Universities a student applicant had applied to, including possibly suspending or closing an applicant’s on-line account upon notice to the student, when we have reason to believe that accessing and/or disclosing this information or taking such action is necessary to prevent, identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating any of our on-line user agreements or policies or who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) Common Application rights or property, other Common Application users, members or schools, or to help protect anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. Common Application may also disclose or access registered user information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative, technical and other related purposes that we deem necessary to maintain or improve our services. Common Application also reserves the right in its sole discretion to remove any College or University as a member without any further or special notice.

 **What are your choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information, including your rights to “opt-in” or “opt-out”?**

You have the right not to provide us with any personal information about you when you visit the site but you will not be able to utilize the service that Common Application provides unless you voluntarily decide to complete an on-line User Registration form and answer the required fields. When you first register with the Common Application site, you are given the option to “opt-in” and “opt-out” of receiving communication from member Colleges and Universities and having certain personal information released to our member Colleges and Universities on your “My Colleges List” prior to submission of your application to that selected member College or University. You must affirmatively “opt-in” or “opt-out” according to your preference. Should you “opt-in,” you can later change your mind and “opt-out” for any member College or University by using the “Unsubscribe” link located at the bottom of the email you receive from that member College or University. Alternatively, you may “opt-out” for all member Colleges and Universities by appropriately changing the setting located at your “Update Account” page.

Should you choose to “opt-in,” the following personal information will be released to your designated member Colleges and Universities: Prefix, First Name, Middle Name, Last Name, Suffix, Preferred Name, Address1, Address2, City, State, ZIP, Country, Ethnicity, Sex, ApplicantID, Citizenship Status, Home Phone, Cell Phone, Fax, Email, DOB, SSN, Entry Term, Decision Type, Applicant Type (First Year or Transfer), Academic Interest, Paid Status, School Officials, IM Address, IM provider, School CEEB and School Name. Your “opting-in” will also allow member Colleges and Universities to use the Common Application email system to contact you at anytime.

Should you choose the default “opt-out” option, everything that is released to your selected member Colleges and Universities under the “opt-in” option above is also released except for the following information: Address1, Address2, Home Phone, Cell Phone, Fax, Email, SSN and IM Address. In addition, your decision to adopt the default “opt-out” setting shall prevent member Colleges and Universities from using the Common Application email system to contact you until such time as you submit an application, supplement, or payment to that member College or University.

Once registered, while you are free not to provide any personal information requested on the Common Application®, any application supplement or other applicant form, to do so may cause the member College and/or University that you select not to accept the application, supplement or other applicant form as complete and consequently delay the application admission process or reject the submission as incomplete regardless of payment. Users/applicants can also decide not to provide information that is designated as “optional” on any application, supplement or other form and still utilize the service upon which we provide. Users should communicate with their designated College and/or University directly if any admission application is delayed or rejected or otherwise results in an outcome that does not satisfy the applicant’s expectations.

You have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies you will likely be unable to use those Common Application™ services that require registration in order to participate.

 **What is Common Application’s policy on allowing you to access, update, correct, or delete your personally identifiable information?**

You may access and edit your registration information by using your Common Application User ID and password. If you have forgotten your password (links to “forgot password” feature) to have your password emailed to you. For all other problems signing in to Common Application and complete this form. Unfortunately, absent extenuating circumstances which you must specifically communicate to us in a signed writing, we do not allow you to delete your registration information or to deactivate your registration information account. See “What are the kind of security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information including credit card information and how is your information stored, accessed and used by others?“

The Common Application, through its independent trustworthy web service provider will make reasonable efforts to see that your instructions to make revisions to your personal information are made. For any information that was erroneously provided by the applicant but was already submitted and can no longer be changed or re-submitted, you must contact the College/University or credit card processor directly to alert them to the erroneous information. Please click here (links to the “instruction” page) for further instructions on this matter.

You may also update your email address within your on-line profile, application or supplement, though once your email address information has been submitted to your selected member college/university, you can only update your email address if you contact that member college/university directly.

 **What are the kind of security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information including credit card information and how is your information stored, accessed and used by others?**

Your User Registration information is password-protected. You may edit your User Registration information by using your Common Application User ID and password.

We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. Also remember to sign out of your Common Application registration account and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet “cafe.” Also, to help ensure the security of your application, do not copy and paste links from within the online application into an email or share with others on a public forum. If you do not log out of the online system, users with technical knowledge may use these links to access your online application.

When you make submissions of the Common Application, supplements or other applicant forms to designated member Colleges or Universities or when you access your user registered account information from our web site, we offer the use of a secure server. The secure server software encrypts all information you input before it is sent to us, including your credit card information. We also restrict access to the secure server through the use of firewalls.

When you give Common Application personal information on-line, that information is only viewed by Common Application and its trustworthy independent web service provider for the sole purpose of providing technical support for the services being provided to you. This information is then accessed by the designated member Colleges and/or Universities with whom you select by logging into the secure system of our trustworthy independent web site service provider. Consequently, your personal information can then be viewed, printed and/or exported electronically to the designated member Colleges and/or Universities which are located outside and separate from the Common Application web site and outside of the jurisdiction and perhaps country where you originally entered the information.

Credit Card Payments: The Common Application, working with our trustworthy independent web service provider, allows applicants to pay admissions application fees online using a credit card. This feature is designed to accept ONE credit card transaction if you click “Submit” ONE time. However, if you click “Submit” more than once, it is possible your account will have a duplicate charge. Our member Colleges and/or Universities will reverse charges for any duplicate transaction. HOWEVER, NEITHER COMMON APPLICATION, INC., ITS MEMBER COLLEGES OR UNIVERSITIES, NOR THIRD PARTY INDEPENDENT CONTRACTORS OF COMMON APPLICATION, INC. WILL BE RESPONSIBLE FOR REFUNDING ANY PROCESSING FEES INCURRED BY INCORRECT USE OF THIS FEATURE. Accordingly, to avoid duplicate charges, please do not click the credit card SUBMIT button more than once! Your credit card information is not stored by us but is immediately transmitted under encryption to your designated credit card processor, and none of your personal information is stored on your computer or a computer of the college that would allow someone to by-pass the login authentication procedures.

The Common Application web site, through its trustworthy independent web server provider’s secure server, retains your personal information for the entire application admissions cycle which ends on or about July 15 of each calendar year. Once the web site closes for the academic year in July, your personal information is removed or “archived” off the “live” servers and “backed-up” to a separate secured remote server for storage (at least until overwritten when space is needed to back-up more recent data) where no one can access it except on a very limited basis by us or our trustworthy independent web service provider. Unless under order of subpoena, your application once archived remains irretrievable. Therefore, you are strongly advised to print out for your own records a hard copy of all Common Application® forms that you have completed.

Note that the reasons for granting us continued limited access to your personal information from the remote server may include, but are not necessarily limited to, allowing us, our trustworthy independent web service provider or other partners, or member Colleges/Universities to compile statistical or historical information about the previous year’s applications.  For statistical purposes, your personal information will be used only in the aggregate meaning that personal identifying information such as your name and social security number shall not be used.  For some historical purposes, however, we and our trustworthy independent web service provider or other partners, including member Colleges/Universities will have continued access to your archived personal identifying information as we and/or our trustworthy independent web service provider or other partners deem necessary.

Please note that whenever your personal information is handled as described above, regardless of where this occurs, steps are taken to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with this Policy. Unfortunately, however, no data transmission over the Internet or electronic handling can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us online, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. However, we cannot accept liability for disclosure of any personal information due to errors in transmission or unauthorized acts of third parties.

 **Your California Privacy Rights**

If you are a California “consumer,” upon your request (see Section entitled “Additional information and how you can contact us regarding this Policy“), we will disclose to you what personal information of yours was shared with what trustworthy third party provider within the last year (including disclosing to you our provider’s name and address) if such information was ever used by our provider for their marketing purposes. Note that our current trustworthy third party providers have agreed not to use your information for this purpose, however.

California Civil Code §1798.83 entitles residents of California to request information about the third parties that Common Application has shared personal information in the immediately preceding calendar year if those third parties ever used such information for direct marketing purposes. California residents may submit one request per calendar year in the form of a report that details: (a) what type of information Common Application shared, (b) with whom Common Application shared such information and (c) the nature of the third party business.

California residents may submit their request by scrolling to the Section entitled “Additional information and how you can contact us regarding this Policy” and by clicking where it says “click here.”

 **Does Common Application have an identity theft policy?**

While rare, the risk of identity theft to on-line users of the internet is on the rise and The Common Application recognizes the importance of taking steps to help its student applicants, users, customers and members identify and detect patterns, practices or activities that may indicate the existence of identity theft involving the Common App Online service or the Common Application web site, including implementing the appropriate actions or responses to help safeguard against and/or mitigate the risk of future or continued theft.  Please read carefully the identity theft portions of this Policy (Sections 11-15) before using the Common App Online service or its web site.

The identity theft portions of this Policy is to help all Common Application users identify identity theft and to provide them with information about what steps The Common Application takes to detect identity theft, safeguard against, respond to and/or mitigate continued or future identity theft involving the Common App Online service or The Common Application web site.

Please also note that the identity theft portions of this Policy also only addresses Common Application’s identity theft policy concerning activities involving its own web site and service and it does not apply to activities or identity theft policies of others or other web sites independent from or linked to the Common Application web site, such as web sites or IT systems of secondary schools, member colleges or universities or other third parties or any individuals or officials that may be associated with these other institutions or third parties.

 **What kinds of patterns, practices or activities may indicate the existence of identity theft?**

In order to be on-guard for possible identity theft, all student applicants, users, customers and members should be aware of the potential indicators of identity theft. These may include but are not necessarily limited to the following:

  * Receiving an alert, notification or warning from a consumer reporting agency
  * Receiving notification of a credit freeze or address discrepancy
  * Receiving notification of an abnormal increase in the number of credit inquiries, new credit relationships or new credit uses
  * Receiving notification of an account being involuntarily closed or a credit abuse being identified
  * Receiving or becoming aware of suspicious documents, information or photos provided for identification that appear to have been altered or forged or are inconsistent with other authenticated and accessible personal identifying information
  * Receiving or becoming aware of suspicious documents, information or photos provided for identification that appear to be associated with prior fraudulent practices or activities or are attributable to another student applicant, user, customer, member or other third party
  * Any unusual use of or suspicious activity involving or relating to any account that is held with The Common Application

 **What steps does Common Application take to detect identity theft?**

  * The Common Application primarily functions as an information and document conduit between students that apply to various member colleges and universities using the Common App Online service or Common Application web site and the various secondary school officials and members that also utilize the service and site.  While The Common Application through its trustworthy web service provider deploys several security measures to protect the personal identifying information (including credit card information) of its users (see the section on security precautions in place discussed in this Policy), such security measures may not always prevent the crime of identity theft due to the specific nature of this crime.  Accordingly, The Common Application must also rely upon the credible reporting of suspicious patterns, practices or activities of identity theft from its trustworthy student applicants, users, customers, members or school officials.
  * In this connection, any student applicant, user, school official or member that becomes aware of any suspicious pattern, practice or activity suggestive of an identity theft that also involves or relates to the Common App Online service or the Common Application web site are urged to notify the Common Application via email at [privacy@justtotaltech.co.uk](mailto:privacy@justtotaltech.co.uk). Please be sure to disclose your name, all relevant information about the suspected identity theft including information about how you may be contacted.

 **What steps does Common Application take to safeguard against, respond to and/or mitigate continued or future identity theft or breaches of personal data?**

  * Upon receiving credible information about a possible identity theft or other possible related wrongdoing involving or relating to the Common App Online service or the Common Application web site from a trustworthy student applicant, user, customer, member, school official or other trustworthy third party, The justtotaltechlication  will do what it reasonably can to investigate the merits of the claim by gathering up any other information within its reasonable control in order to evaluate whether there has been a possible attempt to commit identity theft or other possible related wrongdoing.  If The Common Application believes there are grounds for believing in good faith that an attempt at wrongdoing was made, The Common Application reserves the right to cancel or close an offending or possible tainted transaction or account, monitor a particular account or line of communication, change applicable security codes, notify law enforcement officials, notify the victim of the alleged attempted fraud or other wrong doing, provide to the victim certain information (including the personal identifying information of another user) if reasonably requested or justified and/or do such other acts reasonable and/or necessary to protect The Common Application and/or victim of the alleged theft or other possible wrongdoing and otherwise comply with any data breach notification or identity theft law that is applicable to the particular circumstance.  Common Application also reserves the right not to take any action if no such action is warranted. Finally, Common Application reserves the right to rely upon its trustworthy independent web service provider to help implement, safeguard against and/or mitigate continued or future identity theft or other possible wrongdoing involving any student applicant, user, customer, member or school official when the alleged theft or other possible wrongdoing involves or is related to the Common App Online service or the Common Application web site.

Please click here [here](mailto:privacy@justtotaltech.co.uk) to pose any questions, comments, feedback or complaints regarding the identity theft portion of this Policy.

 **Posting of Testimonials**

If you post a testimonial on this Web site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of this site and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit.

 **Additional Information and how you can contact us regarding this Policy**

We encourage you to review the Frequently Asked Questions for additional information and instructions about any questions that you may have regarding this Policy.

Comments, feedback or complaints regarding this Policy or the use of personal information by this web site.

 **Emails That You Send Us**

Please note that any emails that you send us may be copied, forwarded or distributed to our members within our sole discretion.
